Joey!
Miguel?
You're alive...
Does this mean you'll reveal
yourself?
We'll be together again?
No, my child.
I need to finish my mission.
I only came here to see you.
Andrew was telling me
about his coverage in the north.
Drug deal.
Unfortunately,
the mastermind escaped.
Was the deal finalized?
Unfortunately, not.
- Tomas, is that blood?
- I'll just change this bandage.
But it's just his back.
How can we build a case
with that?
No face, no profile.
I picked this up
when Berdugo was escaping.
- There's something engraved.
- Maybe those are initials.
What's more important?
Andrew or your business?
Nothing is more important
to me than my family.
Find a way to get rid of him.
No trace, no noise.
My pleasure, Boss.
I'm aware Joey can't join
the raid.
But in my understanding,
she can...
She can still be part of it,
I mean.
Even in pre-planning.
But you invoked protocol.
That's why she was cut out
completely, right?
And it feels like...
I betrayed her.
So, I just want to know
if it's really just protocol
or was it meant to...
cut her out completely.
Andrew, if I wanted to shut her
out because she was an obstacle,
I would never use my position.
I wouldn't hide behind protocol.
Andrew, we have history,
memories.
We have a past that you
and she don't have,
and that can't be erased.
That's where I have
the advantage.
Andrew...
I really want us to try again.
Properly this time.
That's why I requested
a transfer here,
and it was approved.
We'll be together more often.
[MELLOW MUSIC]
I'm not good at saying goodbye,
so, I wrote it instead.
But I didn't leave
because I was angry.
I love you, you know.
So, how could I be angry?
If ever our paths cross again,
I hope everything
is more peaceful.
I hope you're truly happy.
I'll miss you.
Peter.
It's heartbreaking, isn't it?
I cried too when I read it.
You read it?
Sorry, Joey.
You took too long to come back.
I got impatient. I read it.
But you know, Joey,
I realized something about you.
What?
Pretty.
Joey, you're so beautiful.
I applaud you.
Think about it.
You have Peter,
you have Jin Ho bae
who I don't even know
if aliens took him or what.
Then you have Boss Idol too.
Girl, you're a fantasy.
You're the fantasy of us gays.
What? They're just my friends.
But honestly,
I do miss Jin Ho and Peter.
Maybe if they were here,
they could help me and...
Who?
What is that? Tamaraw? Tarzan?
Is this a person?
What's that, Joey?
No, it's...
it's Tatang,
the old man in our neighborhood.
Because he found another place.
You know, girl, try this.
It's delicious.
At least you'll get salty
about the boys.
Is this good?
It's good, I'm telling you.
[CRUNCHES]
Delicious. What's this?
"Crispy mushroom."
[DAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING]
Lumen-X?
That's a party drug.
Popular among the youth.
It has a component
of magic mushroom.
[SNAPS]
Hey, why? Isn't it tasty?
No, it's super tasty.
Can I take a picture
so I can buy it?
See? I told you.
[DAUNTING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CAMERA SHUTTER SNAPS]
Thank you very much.
[PHONE CHIMES]
[DAUNTING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[PHONE RINGING]
- Let me answer this, okay?
- Sure.
Hello, Dad?
Did you get what I sent?
Yes, child,
the logo and the address.
Yes, Dad.
Good catch, dear.
Looks like I know
where they're making Lumen-X.
Everyone out!
You're early.
Is Berdugo here?
No, he still has a meeting.
That's good too.
Isn't it dangerous for him to be
here in the production area?
He's loyal to me,
meaning he's loyal
to the organization.
He was one of those chasing us
before.
Lisa, many operations failed
because of them
and their companions.
If sabotage was my intention,
this operation wouldn't have
lasted long
after Lisa brought me in.
Well...
this guy actually understands
Tagalog.
So that means you understand...
that I'm not talking to you!
What did he say?
Enough!
Jin Ho, stay out of this.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Lisa, won't this be a hindrance
to our operation?
Wait a minute.
Did I hit my head somewhere
or did something change
in this organization
without anyone telling me?
Because last time I checked,
I invested in this organization.
Berdugo might keep me
beneath him,
but I bring capital, leverage,
and I pay the men here.
Men like you, Matias.
I'm very much aware
that Berdugo trusts you,
but that doesn't put you
above me.
So don't talk to me like I work
for you.
Know your place!
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
This man with his back turned,
that's Berdugo,
the creator of this damn drug.
He escaped the operation
in the North,
but I'm sure his world
is shrinking.
And next time,
there won't be any escape.
It's prison time.
You can count on it,
Tirada viewers,
as always.
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Ma'am Rebecca...
take your medicine.
Thank you.
Clarissa...
The news I used to report
was bad,
but now it's worse.
Like this...
Like Andrew's report.
Ma'am.
Social media is really toxic
now.
Even I stopped using it.
Better. Good for you.
Good thing...
Good thing my grandchildren
are here.
They're the only ones
I should look at.
They relieve stress.
That's true, Ma'am.
You're lucky.
It's really fun to watch them.
They're happy,
they live a comfortable life.
Then let me just remind you,
Rebecca.
It wasn't this network
that gave you the safety
and comfortable life
you have now.
It was me, Rebecca.
Ma'am, did I say something
wrong?
No.
I just remembered something.
Mom...
Are you okay?
Lately, you seem a bit distant
and distracted, Mom.
I'm fine.
It's...
It's probably my medicines.
I take so many.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
Harris, grandson.
Yes?
Where's Kisses?
Kisses is already asleep,
Grandmother.
You remember the brown stuffed
bear I gave her
for her birthday?
The brown one?
The brown...
yes.
- Harold, right?
- Yeah, yeah.
Yes.
Where is it?
Mom, I stored it in the
warehouse
so it wouldn't gather dust.
Why, Mom?
Do you need it?
I just remembered.
But can I see it?
- I'll get it for you, Mom.
- We'll get it for you, Mom.
Thank you.
[DAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING]
I'll just get this.
Thank you.
[DAUNTING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[DAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING]
Ma'am...
What are you doing?
Is there anything I can help you
with?
You surprised me, Clarissa.
Nothing, you can't help.
Here.
What is that?
It's a spy camera attached
to the eye of the stuffed toy.
And why do you need that?
Ma'am Rebecca, I'm not going
to do anything bad to you.
I'm not a bad person, Ma'am.
I know.
And this isn't for you.
There's someone I need to catch.
It needs to stop.
It needs to end here
before my family gets hurt.
Ma'am, what are you saying?
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
Joey.
Joey, what are you doing here?
I'm picking up my mother.
[DOORBELL CHIMES]
Wait, wait, Joey.
Aren't we going to talk about
what happened to us
in the north?
Which one?
There were many.
The drug deal, Berdugo,
what happened with you and Zoey.
What happened with us.
Can you please not be loud?
What "us"?
Someone might hear you and think
we're still together.
Then Zoey will fight
with me again.
Can we not bring Zoey into this?
Wow, protective?
Oh, please.
You're the one who insisted
she join our mission.
You even excluded me,
didn't you?
Don't say you don't know
about protocol,
-you even made a deal with them.
-No, Joey.
You know, because...
Good evening, Sir Andrew.
Is Mommy Clarissa here?
Are you Joey?
She's inside.
Wait a moment, I'll open
the door for Sir Andrew,
then we'll go in, okay?
No need, Miss,
just escort Joey.
I'll take care of this.
All right. Come on.
This way.
[SENTIMENTAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[KNOCK ON THE DOOR]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Come in!
[DOOR CLOSE]
You wanted to talk to me,
Rebecca?
I don't want to lie
to my family anymore.
Tell them who you really are!
That was quite sudden, Rebecca.
And "who I really am?"
You mean the man who kept
this family afloat,
paid the bills, fixed the mess?
Who made sure your children
and grandchildren never
lacked anything
while you were cared
for by your physical therapists
and private nurses?
Which, by the way,
I'm still paying for.
You're the reason I ended up
like this!
Now, I want you to tell them
everything
because I'm sick and tired
of all your lies.
I've carried them long enough.
Tell your family who you
really are,
that you are the leader
of a syndicate,
that illegal drugs
are your business,
and that you are Berdugo!
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Here's the address, look.
Yes, this is it.
But this isn't a factory.
This is our house.
We've lived here a long time,
and I don't know of any mushroom
chips factory in our area.
All right.
[PHONE RINGING]
Sir?
I just read your message.
What are you doing there
in Sta. Isabel?
Sir, I feel Berdugo's laboratory
is here.
The address listed is different.
So, we wouldn't track them
I presume.
But I think, Sir, we're close.
Come, come in.
Sit down first, Joey.
I'll just tell your mother
you're here.
I think she's still doing
something in the kitchen.
Thank you.
All right.
I'll leave you for now.
[SENTIMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING]
Joey.
I just want to be clear.
I did not intend to kick you out
of the operations.
It was protocol.
Protocol again.
Do you think I'll really believe
you didn't know I'd be excluded?
You're a journalist.
You're smart.
So, it's impossible
you didn't know I'd be barred
from that operation
from the start.
I know.
See? You admitted it.
Yes, yes, but wait.
I knew, but I realized it late.
You think they'll believe you?
A woman in constant pain,
on heavy meds, emotional?
What do you think they'll hear?
Maybe they won't believe me
because you poisoned
their minds,
because you touched
their hearts.
But I know there are still those
who will believe me.
Your lies should end tonight.
I'm going to tell my children.
- [GRUNTING]
- [SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
Joey...
Sir Andrew.
Miss Clarissa.
Are you here to visit
Ma'am Rebecca?
Yes, Miss Clarissa.
By the way,
my sister mentioned that my mom
feels comfortable with you,
and that rarely happens
with her caregivers.
Well, your mom is kind.
Are we going home?
Dear, that's what I was going
to tell you.
I'm not finished preparing
Ma'am Rebecca's herbal medicine.
Ma'am Yvette will just let
the driver bring me home.
But I was thinking,
what about you?
I'll take Joey home,
Miss Clarissa.
Oh no, don't.
You'll be inconvenienced.
Don't.
No, it's okay because mommy
will sleep later anyway, right?
And just think of it
as my way of repaying
all the good you've done
for my mom.
I don't want to.
Don't be like that to your mom.
Don't add to her problems, Joey.
Come on.
[DAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING]
Go on, Joey.
Sir Andrew is offering anyway.
It would be rude to refuse.
Go on.
Shall we go?
Text me, Mom, okay?
I'll wait for you to get home.
All right.
Text me too when you get home?
- All right.
- Love you.
Love you.
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm telling my children now!
- [SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [GRUNTING]
- [THUDS]
- [GROANS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV]
I feel no mercy for you anymore.
- [THUDDING]
- [GROANING]
You've been too emotional
lately.
- [INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV]
- [GROANING]
This should help you relax.
By this time tomorrow,
you won't even remember this
conversation.
- [STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
- [GRAPS]
- [INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV]
- [STIRRING MUSIC CONTINUES]
Bro.
Do you know if there's a food
processing factory
here in Sta. Isabel?
None, Bro.
None?
They're making mushroom chips.
None, Sir.
- All right, thanks.
- All right, Sir.
- [REVVING]
- [DAUNTING MUSIC PLAYING]
[BRAZEN MUSIC PLAYING]
Sir.
Can you check this?
All right.
[BRAZEN MUSIC CONTINUES]
Is that the Korean, your crush?
He's not my crush, okay.
Jin Ho is just really funny.
[BRAZEN MUSIC CONTINUES]
[CAMERA SHUTTER SNAPS]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER ON TV]
Ma'am Rebecca...
[STIRRING MUSIC PLAYING]
Ma'am Rebecca?
Ma'am Rebecca...
What did you do, Ma'am Rebecca?
Ma'am Rebecca!
Ma'am Yvette!
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
Your Korean friend,
do you still talk to him?
Maybe he already caught
the syndicate member
he was looking for.
Please save my mommy.
What happened?
Why did you leave her alone?
I can't handle it if something
happens to Ma'am Rebecca.
There's no Lee Jin Ho
in the database.
That only means one thing.
He's not Korean police.
- She's in critical condition.
- It looks intentional.
- Mommy couldn't have done that.
- Andrew...
Let's start CPR.
Mom, fight, please.
You cannot live, Rebecca.
They cannot know the truth.